RG 004:023, Canton Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Canton Probate Court records
1841-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Canton District)
47.5 cubic feet
Probate record books, 1841-1940; Probate files, 1841-1976.
RG004_023
1915-027, 2011-015, 2011-016, T003286
Historical Note
Hartford County, Town established in May 1806, Parent Town: Simsbury
The Canton Probate District was constituted June 7, 1841 from the Simsbury Probate District. It served the municipality of Canton. The Canton Probate District merged on January 5, 2011 with the Avon, Granby, and Simsbury Probate Districts to create the Simsbury Regional Probate District which serves the municipalities of Avon, Canton, Granby, and Simsbury.
Town of Canterbury, Probate District chronology:
May 1806 - June 6, 1841 Simsbury District
June 7, 1841 - January 4, 2011, Canton District
January 5, 2001 - present, Simbury Regional Probate District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-20, 1841-1940. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 20. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1841-1976. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. Accession T003285 includes conservator records that pre-date the creation of the Canterbury District.
Inventory control book, 1841-1944 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 20. There are two Volume 2s, one is of records and the other is of bonds. There is also an unnumbered bond volume. There are two Volumes 9s, one is of records and the other is of decrees.
Probate files are arranged by accession. Each accession is arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1915-027 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: There is no index for the probate files in Accession T003286.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-016.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Canton
Places:
Canton(Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1976 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-016, Record books, 1841-1940; and Accession 2011-016, Probate files, 1922-1976, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-4, 6, 8-9, 11-12, 14-16, 1841-1916; probate files, 1841-1944 (Accession 1915-027); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1915-027 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): December 9, 1911 (1833-1920); November 3, 1921 (1837-1920); March 15, 1930 (1902-1928); March 27, 1936 (1903-1935); April 25, 1951 (1925-1950). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
It is not known when the probate files in accession T003286 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library.
The record books in accession 2011-015 and the probate files in accession 2011-016 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on December 9, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1841-1940; 13.5 cubic feet; 2011-016
  - Records, 1841-1848 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1847-1855 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1855-1866 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1865-1873 (Volume 4)
  - Decrees, 1869-1884 (Volume 5)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1873-1887 (Volume 6)
  - Decrees, 1884-1889 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1887-1894 (Volume 8)
  - Decrees, 1888-1898 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1894-1903 (Volume 9)
  - Decrees, 1902-1905 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1903-1907 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1907-1909 (Volume 12)
  - Decrees, 1907-1915 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1909-1911 (Volume 14)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Records, 1911-1913 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1913-1916 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1916-1917 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1917-1920 (Volume 18)
  - Decrees, 1915-1921 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1920-1925 (Volume 20)
  - Bonds, 1881-1918 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Bonds, 1918-1940 (Volume 2)
  - Probate Court letters, 1903-1910 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Return of notice publications, 1889-1910 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Newspaper notices, 1910-1916 (Volume unnumbered)
- Probate files, 1841-1944; 13 cubic feet; 1915-027
  - Ackart - Atwater (Drawer 1)
  - Bachand - Barbour (Drawer 2)
  - Barker - Bidwell, J. (Drawer 3)
  - Bidwell, K. - Bradley (Drawer 4)
  - Brainard - Bruyette (Drawer 5)
  - Burgess - Carrier (Drawer 6)
  - Carter - Case, E. (Drawer 7)
  - Case, F. - Case, John (Drawer 8)
  - Case, Joseph - Case, Q. (Drawer 9)
  - Case, R. - Case, Z. (Drawer 10)
  - Castonguay - Church (Drawer 11)
  - Clark - Cowles, J. (Drawer 12)
  - Cowles, K. - Doane (Drawer 13)
  - Dubrick - Eggleston (Drawer 14)
  - Eklof - Flannery (Drawer 15)
  - Flarity - Gawialis (Drawer 16)
  - German - Gustafson (Drawer 17)
  - Hale - Hemler (Drawer 18)
  - Henney - Hoffman (Drawer 19)
  - Hohbein - Hugins, C. (Drawer 20)
  - Hugins, D. - Jenkins, B. (Drawer 21)
  - Jenkins, C. - Kelley (Drawer 22)
  - Killany - Lawrence (Drawer 23)
  - Lawton - McFarland (Drawer 24)
  - McGarriagle - Merrel (Drawer 25)
  - Merrill - Mills, G. (Drawer 26)
  - Mills, H. - Neal (Drawer 27)
  - Nearing - Ostrowski (Drawer 28)
  - Page - Phillips (Drawer 29)
  - Pierce - Reed, C. (Drawer 30)
  - Reed, D. - Ronan, J. (Drawer 31)
  - Ronan, K. - Schwartz (Drawer 32)
  - Sears - Smith, H. (Drawer 33)
  - Smith, J. - Standish (Drawer 34)
  - Stark - Thompson (Drawer 35)
  - Thorp - Wagner, K. (Drawer 36)
  - Wagner, L. - Widen (Drawer 37)
  - Wilcox - Woodford (Drawer 38)
  - Woodruff - Z; Miscellaneous (Drawer 39)
- Inventory control book, 1841-1944; T003073
  Index of the five accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1915-027
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, circa 1945-1955; 5 cubic feet; T003286
  - Adams - Belden (Drawer 1)
  - Benham - Bristol (Drawer 2)
  - Brown - Croteau (Drawer 3)
  - Crowley - Danne (Drawer 4)
  - Eagleson - Godin (Drawer 5)
  - Goldstein - Hart (Drawer 6)
  - Hemsley - Hult (Drawer 7)
  - Humphrey - Kloppenburg (Drawer 8)
  - Knowles - Lane (Drawer 9)
  - Langer - Moroney (Drawer 10)
  - Myers - Potts (Drawer 11)
  - Provost - Scharr (Drawer 12)
  - Schmidt - Steed (Drawer 13)
  - Stevens - Wagner (Drawer 14)
  - Wahatalo - Z (Drawer 15)
- Probate files, 1922-1976; 16 cubic feet; 2011-016
  - Abbott - Bellerose (Box 1)
  - Bergeron - Brown, A. (Box 2)
  - Brown, K. - Chineis (Box 3)
  - Clarke - Dobrick (Box 4)
  - Dodge - Finkle, H. (Box 5)
  - Finckle, M. - Graham (Box 6)
  - Grant - Hood (Box 7)
    There are files outside of this range in this box
  - Higley - Johnson, E. (Box 8)
  - Johnson, K. - Leahy, A. (Box 9)
  - Leahy, T. - Matthews (Box 10)
  - Maturo - Myers, T. (Box 11)
  - Myers, T. - Pope (Box 12)
  - Potter - Savik (Box 13)
  - Schiedel - Suominen (Box 14)
  - Sullivan - Wheeler, M. (Box 15)
  - Wheeler, M. - Zils (Box 16)